Guide to the James E. Jackson Audiotapes Collection OH.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Lectures, Speeches, 452677
  - The Party (2) [bad], Undated; cuid13876; 452811 (Cassette 203)
  - The Party (2-3), Undated; cuid13877; 452810 (Cassette 204)
  - The Party (4-5), Undated; cuid13878; 452809 (Cassette 205)
  - The Party (6-7), Undated; cuid13879; 452808 (Cassette 206)
  - On the Party, May 1981; cuid13880; 452807 (Cassette 207)
  - The Party (2), May 28, 1981; cuid13881; 452806 (Cassette 208)
  - Party Birthday, Aug 1977; cuid13882; 452805 (Cassette 209)
  - Party History; Party School, Mar 1975; cuid13883; 452804 (Cassette 210)
  - Party History (1), Mar 1975; cuid13884; 452803 (Cassette 211)
  - Party History (2), Mar 1975; cuid13885; 452802 (Cassette 212)
  - Party History (2), Mar 1975; cuid13886; 452801 (Cassette 213)
  - Party History (3), Mar 1975; cuid13887; 452800 (Cassette 214)
  - Party History (4), Mar 1975; cuid13888; 452799 (Cassette 215)
  - Party Organization with Mike Welch, Aug 1974; cuid13889; 452798 (Cassette 216)
  - Side 1: Party Organization with Mike Welch; Side 2: Blank, Aug 1974; cuid13890; 452797 (Cassette 217)
  - On Party Platform, May 25, 1979; cuid13891; 452796 (Cassette 218)
  - Party Theory, Mar 1975; cuid13892; 452795 (Cassette 219)
  - Party Theory, Party School, Mar 1975; cuid13893; 452794 (Cassette 220)
  - Party Theory, Mar 1975; cuid13894; 452793 (Cassette 221)
  - Party / Youth, Undated; cuid13895; 452792 (Cassette 222)
  - Side 1: Party; Side 2: United Front (2), Undated; cuid13896; 452791 (Cassette 223)
  - Party / Youth (8), Undated; cuid13897; 452790 (Cassette 224)
  - Paul Robeson Commemoration - New Zealand's Tribute, Aug 1976; cuid13898; 452789 (Cassette 225)
  - Peace History of the Party's Position on African-American Equality, Undated; cuid13899; 452788 (Cassette 226)
  - Peace Workshop, Undated; cuid13900; 452787 (Cassette 227)
  - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (2), Undated; cuid13901; 452786 (Cassette 228)
  - Peace Workshop, Milwaukee (3), Undated; cuid13902; 452785 (Cassette 229)
  - Side 1: Weinstock, L.: Trade Unione Movement, Bio - Dr. W.E.B. Du Bois; Side 2: Jackson, J.: Petty Burgeois Nationalism (1), Undated; cuid13903; 452784 (Cassette 230)
  - Petty Burgeois Nationalism (2), Undated; cuid13904; 452783 (Cassette 231)
  - Philosophy, Undated; cuid13905; 452782 (Cassette 232)
  - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Historical Materialism, Undated; cuid13906; 452781 (Cassette 233)
  - Philosophy (2), Mar 1977; cuid13907; 452780 (Cassette 234)
  - Philosophy (3), Mar 1977; cuid13908; 452779 (Cassette 235)
  - Philosophy, Oct 1982; cuid13909; 452778 (Cassette 236)
  - Side 1: Philosophy; Side 2: Dialectical Materialism, Oct 1982; cuid13910; 452777 (Cassette 237)
  - Philosophy / Dialectical MaterialismNational School, Mar 1977; cuid13911; 452776 (Cassette 238)
  - Philosophy, Dialectics (4), Dec 1975; cuid13912; 452775 (Cassette 239)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers (2)AYD Reports, TM Report, Dec 1975; cuid13913; 452774 (Cassette 240)
  - Philosophical Falsifiers (3), Dec 1975; cuid13914; 452773 (Cassette 241)
  - Political Economy, Undated; cuid13915; 452772 (Cassette 242)
  - Political Economy, Undated; cuid13916; 452771 (Cassette 243)
  - Political Economy (3-4), Undated; cuid13917; 452770 (Cassette 244)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Inflation, Undated; cuid13918; 452769 (Cassette 245)
  - Side 1: Political Economy / Inflation; Side 2: Socialism, Undated; cuid13919; 452768 (Cassette 246)
  - Political Economy, Aug 1974; cuid13920; 452767 (Cassette 247)
  - Political Economy, Feb 1975; cuid13921; 452766 (Cassette 248)
  - Political Economy, Commodity ProductionLecture and Afterword Session, Feb 1975; cuid13922; 452765 (Cassette 249)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Accumulation of the Capital, Feb 1975; cuid13923; 452764 (Cassette 250)
  - Side 1: Lumer, Hy: Monetary Crisis; Side 2: Jackson, James: Political Economy Review (2), Dec 1975; cuid13924; 452763 (Cassette 251)
  - Political Economy, Jan 1976; cuid13925; 452762 (Cassette 252)
  - Side 1: Political Economy; Side 2: Questioning Students, Jan 1976; cuid13926; 452761 (Cassette 253)
  - Political Economy, Jan 1976; cuid13927; 452760 (Cassette 254)
  - Political Economy, Jul 1976; cuid13928; 452759 (Cassette 255)
  - Political Economy (1), Mar 1977; cuid13929; 452758 (Cassette 256)
  - Political Economy (2), Mar 1977; cuid13930; 452757 (Cassette 257)
  - Political Economy (3), Mar 1977; cuid13931; 452756 (Cassette 258)
  - Political Economy, Questions on (3), Mar 1977; cuid13932; 452755 (Cassette 259)
  - Political Economy, Aug 1977; cuid13933; 452754 (Cassette 260)
  - Political Economy, Jul 1978; cuid13934; 452753 (Cassette 261)
  - Political Economy (final), Jul 1978; cuid13935; 452752 (Cassette 262)
  - Politics and Revolution (2)National School, Mar 1977; cuid13936; 452751 (Cassette 263)
  - Portland, Maine Radio, Oct 1986; cuid13937; 452750 (Cassette 264)
  - Side 1: Principles of Party Organization and Functioning; Side 2: Industrial Concentration, Feb 1976; cuid13938; 452749 (Cassette 265)
  - Q&A On Children; Soviet Prophet, Undated; cuid13939; 452748 (Cassette 266)
  - Questions and Report from GRPS, Undated; cuid13940; 452747 (Cassette 267)
  - Questions for James E. Jackson, Undated; cuid13941; 452746 (Cassette 268)
  - Racism (5-6?), Undated; cuid13942; 452745 (Cassette 269)
  - Side 1: Racism; Side 2: Cont'd + Q&A's, Undated; cuid13943; 452744 (Cassette 270)
  - Racism, Fight Against, Undated; cuid13944; 452743 (Cassette 271)
  - Side 1: Racism with Mike Welch; Side 2: Party Organization with Mike Welch, Aug 1974; cuid13945; 452742 (Cassette 272)
  - Report back from Workshops (Jackson, J.; Meyers, G.), Undated; cuid13946; 452741 (Cassette 273)
  - Report on 60th Anniversary of Soviet Union, Dec 1977; cuid13947; 452740 (Cassette 274)
  - Report on Trip to China, Jul 1988; cuid13948; 452739 (Cassette 275)
  - Revolution Process / Components of Revolution, Aug 1977; cuid13949; 452738 (Cassette 276)
  - Revolutionary Conditions, Jan 1976; cuid13950; 452737 (Cassette 277)
  - School Evaluation (1), Feb 1976; cuid13951; 452736 (Cassette 278)
  - School Evaluation (2), Feb 1976; cuid13952; 452735 (Cassette 279)
  - School Graduation, Closing Speech, Mar 1975; cuid13953; 452734 (Cassette 280)
  - Situation of Black Americans, May 1979; cuid13954; 452733 (Cassette 281)
  - Social Economics 2/12, Undated; cuid13955; 452732 (Cassette 282)
  - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Discussion and Reports 2/28, Undated; cuid13956; 452731 (Cassette 283)
  - Side 1: Social Revolution; Side 2: Questions on Political Economy, Mar 1977; cuid13957; 452730 (Cassette 284)
  - Socialism, Undated; cuid13958; 452729 (Cassette 285)
  - Side 1: Socialism; Side 2: Lenin, the Party, Style in Leadership, Mar 1973; cuid13959; 452728 (Cassette 286)
  - On Socialism (3), May 1981; cuid13960; 452727 (Cassette 287)
  - On Socialism (4), May 1981; cuid13961; 452726 (Cassette 288)
  - Socialism and Communism (1), Undated; cuid13962; 452725 (Cassette 289)
  - Socialism and the Soviet Union, Aug 1979; cuid13963; 452724 (Cassette 290)
  - Socialist Convention / Unemployment (4), May 1979; cuid13964; 452723 (Cassette 291)
  - Socialist Revolution, Aug 1977; cuid13965; 452722 (Cassette 292)
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (1), Undated; cuid13966; 452721 (Cassette 293, Box Digitized Access Files, File cuid13966)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 60 min.
  - Southern Negro Youth Congress Form (2), Undated; cuid13967; 452720 (Cassette 294, Box Digitized Access Files, E-records cuid13967)
    Format: 1/8" audiocassette, Duration: 62 min.
  - Soviet Union, Undated; cuid13968; 452719 (Cassette 295)
  - Soviet Union, Aug 1974; cuid13969; 452718 (Cassette 296)
  - Soviet Union, Jul 1981; cuid13970; 452717 (Cassette 297)
  - On the Soviet Union Berlin Conference, Undated; cuid13971; 452716 (Cassette 298)
  - Staff Seminar Discussion, May 1979; cuid13972; 452715 (Cassette 299)
  - Side 1: The State; Side 2: Q&A, Undated; cuid13973; 452714 (Cassette 300)
  - The State, Feb 1975; cuid13974; 452713 (Cassette 301)
  - The State, Feb 1975; cuid13975; 452712 (Cassette 302)
  - Steel Strikes (?) and Socialism, Jul 1977; cuid13976; 452711 (Cassette 303)
  - Side 1: Strategy; Side 2: United Front, Tactics, Sectarianism with M. Welch, S. Douglas, Aug 1974; cuid13977; 452710 (Cassette 304)
  - Strategy and Tactics (2), Undated; cuid13978; 452709 (Cassette 305)
  - Side 1: Strategy and Tactics; Side 2: Irish Struggles, Mar 1977; cuid13979; 452708 (Cassette 306)
  - Strategy and Tactics, Aug 1977; cuid13980; 452707 (Cassette 307)
  - Strategy and Tactics with Gus Hall, Apr 1988; cuid13981; 452706 (Cassette 308)
  - Side 1: On Strategy and Tactics / Introduction of L. Dlugan; Side 2: Dlugan, Lee: Monopoly Prices and Profits, Imperialism / Historical, Jan 1976; cuid13982; 452705 (Cassette 309)
  - Suslov, In Memorial To, Undated; cuid13983; 452704 (Cassette 310)
  - Side 1: Theory of Knowledge; Side 2: Blank, Jan 1976; cuid13984; 452703 (Cassette 311)
  - Trade Union, Undated; cuid13985; 452702 (Cassette 312)
  - Side 1: Trade Union (White; Jackson, J.); Side 2: Woman Question(White; Jackson, J.), Undated; cuid13986; 452701 (Cassette 313)
  - Side 1: Trade Union; Side 2: National Question, Undated; cuid13987; 452700 (Cassette 314)
  - Trade Union Meeting or Conference, Undated; cuid13988; 452699 (Cassette 315)
  - Transition to Social Revolution and Left Center, Undated; cuid13989; 452698 (Cassette 316)
  - Trotsky, Undated; cuid13990; 452697 (Cassette 317)
  - Trotskyism, Undated; cuid13991; 452696 (Cassette 318)
  - United Front, Undated; cuid13992; 452695 (Cassette 319)
  - United Front (2-3), Undated; cuid13993; 452694 (Cassette 320)
  - United Front (3-4), Undated; cuid13994; 452693 (Cassette 321)
  - Side 1: United Front; Side 2: The YWLL (Young Workers' Liberation League), Undated; cuid13995; 452692 (Cassette 322)
  - Urgent Tasks in Fight for PeaceCentral Committee Report, Nov 1979; cuid13996; 452691 (Cassette 323)
  - VALB Socialist Scholars ConferenceWorkshop includes: Wellman, Saul, Apr 1994; cuid13997; 452690 (Cassette 324)
  - Washington, Feb 1980; cuid13998; 452689 (Cassette 325)
  - WBA I - J. Jackson with Bogdan Denitsch, Jan 1982; cuid13999; 452688 (Cassette 326)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois Memorial Lecture, Boston, Mar 1989; cuid14000; 452687 (Cassette 327)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois: Our Black Titan, Washington, D.C., Feb 1973; cuid14001; 452686 (Cassette 328)
  - West Berlin, Jan 1984; cuid14002; 452685 (Cassette 329)
  - Women's Equality (3-4), Undated; cuid14003; 452684 (Cassette 330)
  - Women's Question, Undated; cuid14004; 452683 (Cassette 331)
  - Women's Question (1) with J. Teixeira, Aug 1977; cuid14005; 452682 (Cassette 332)
  - Women's Question (2), Aug 1977; cuid14006; 452681 (Cassette 333)
  - Women's Question (3), Aug 1977; cuid14007; 452680 (Cassette 334)
  - Working Class History of the Nationalities Wheel (?)22nd Convention, Aug 1979; cuid14008; 452679 (Cassette 335)
  - World Peace CouncilMedal Ceremony for J. Jackson, Undated; cuid14009; 452678 (Cassette 336)
- Series III: Speeches by Others, 452640
  - Bert, Erik: Communist International, Undated; cuid14010; 452676 (Cassette 337)
  - Brodine, M. J.: Asians in America, Feb 1977; cuid14011; 452675 (Cassette 338)
  - Chandra, Romesh: World Peace Council, Jan 1978; cuid14012; 452674 (Cassette 339)
  - Dennis, Ellen with O. Harrington, P. Miriam: Berlin, Nov 1989; cuid14013; 452673 (Cassette 340)
  - Diskin, Louis and Others, Undated; cuid14014; 452672 (Cassette 341)
  - Fitzgerald, Albert: About Himself and about the Unions, Undated; cuid14015; 452671 (Cassette 342)
  - Hall, Gus: Side 1: PA Political Union; Side 2: Boston Conference, Nov 1981; cuid14016; 452670 (Cassette 343)
  - Hall, Gus: Main Address, N.C., Jan 1989; cuid14017; 452669 (Cassette 344)
  - Hall, Gus: On Greece + Q&A's, Undated; cuid14018; 452668 (Cassette 345)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Aug 1988; cuid14019; 452667 (Cassette 346)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Nov 1988; cuid14020; 452666 (Cassette 347)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Jan 1989; cuid14021; 452665 (Cassette 348)
  - Hall, Gus: Update, Feb 1989; cuid14022; 452664 (Cassette 349)
  - Side 1: Hall, Gus Update; Side 2: J. Jackson, Jul 1990; cuid14023; 452663 (Cassette 350)
  - Hudson, Hosea, Undated; cuid14024; 452662 (Cassette 351)
  - Lipschutz, Joan; Jacques, Jeff, Aug 1977; cuid14025; 452661 (Cassette 352)
  - Mobhito, Moses: General Secretary, C.P. South Africa, Mar 28, 1968 (?); cuid14026; 452660 (Cassette 353)
  - Mobhito, Moses; Mullens, Leith; Diskin, Louis, Undated; cuid14027; 452659 (Cassette 354)
  - Side 1: Mora, Grace; Side 2: Winston, Henry, Skit of Students, Mar 1975; cuid14028; 452658 (Cassette 355)
  - Patrinos, Sandy: Strategy and Tactics: Party School, Mar 1975; cuid14029; 452657 (Cassette 356)
  - Shelby: Female Conflicts, Undated; cuid14030; 452656 (Cassette 357)
  - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (2), Mar 1975; cuid14031; 452655 (Cassette 358)
  - Smith, Betty: Party Theory (3), Mar 1975; cuid14032; 452654 (Cassette 359)
  - Side 1: Storey, Rasheed / Afternoon Plenary; Side 2: Afternoon Plenary, Undated; cuid14033; 452653 (Cassette 360)
  - Tyner, Jarvis: Political Report, Mar 1987; cuid14034; 452652 (Cassette 361)
  - Winston, Henry: Communist Party, Dec 1975; cuid14035; 452651 (Cassette 362)
  - Winston, Henry: School Opening, Feb 1978; cuid14036; 452650 (Cassette 363)
  - Winston, Henry Speech (3), Mar 1975; cuid14037; 452649 (Cassette 364)
  - Winston, Henry: Party Theory (3), Party School, Mar 1975; cuid14038; 452648 (Cassette 365)
  - Unknown Speaker (man): Class Struggle, Undated; cuid14039; 452647 (Cassette 366)
  - Unknown Speaker (man)Communist Unity, Undated; cuid14040; 452646 (Cassette 367)
  - Unknown Speaker(s): Discussion on an event at Carnegie Hall, Undated; cuid14041; 452645 (Cassette 368)
  - Unknown speaker (woman): Labor Union and the Party, Undated; cuid14042; 452644 (Cassette 369)
  - Unknown speaker (woman): Martin Luther King, Undated; cuid14043; 452643 (Cassette 370)
  - Unknown speakers: Political Economy - Student Session, Undated; cuid14044; 452642 (Cassette 371)
  - Unknown speakers: Students' Discussions and Presentations on Capitalism, Undated; cuid14045; 452641 (Cassette 372)
- Series IV: 7 inch reel of 1/4 inch-wide Recording Tapes, 452638
  - Patsu, Kofi and other unknown speakers: Young Farmers Rally at Kunnasi Chance, Mar 1965; cuid14046; 452639 (Cassette 373)